Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/joe-dancy-387543b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Real Estate Development Investment Banking Mergers & Acquisitions

Joe Dancy

Director & Senior Vice President at Regions Securities LLC Charlotte, North Carolina

Summary

Over 20 years of banking, entrepreneurial, and energy, power and transportation experience including 14 years as a Corporate and Investment banker in the Energy and Power industry advising many of the nations's largest electric, gas, water, propane and midstream companies on issues related to finance, capital structure, and business growth. I also owned and operated two real estate development and construction companies for 10 years including structuring, marketing, and securing financing with lenders & equity investors for various projects; real estate development, design, and entitlements; project management & construction; and advisory for distressed property valuation and restructurings.

Experience

Regions Securities LLC
Director and Senior Vice President
July 2014 - Present (6 years 1 month)
Charlotte, North Carolina Area

Worked as Senior Coverage Officer in the Energy and Natural Resources Group and currently in the Transportation & Logistics banking group as the senior Debt Products Manager.

US Banccorp Senior Portfolio Manager August 2013 - June 2014 (11 months) Charlotte, North Carolina Area

Senior portfolio manager and underwriter in US Bank's large corporate banking segment.

AREVA NP Finance Lead September 2012 - August 2013 (1 year) Charlotte, North Carolina Area *Primary point of contact with client regarding financial matters on large nuclear construction project.

*Responsible for financial reporting, forecasting, variance analysis, budget support, monitoring of budgeted to actuals, ensuring accuracy of cost data and billing, trend analysis, ad-hoc reporting, etc.

*Responsible for creative problem solving, effective communication and fostering relationships across all levels of project personnel to ensure accuracy of data and understanding of cost controls and procedures.

Dancy Properties, LLC CEO & President August 2003 - September 2012 (9 years 2 months) Charlotte, North Carolina Area

*Owned and operated two real estate companies in Charlotte, NC, specializing in real estate development, project management/construction & design, investment and advisory services.

*Made all executive and financial decisions for the companies, including project selection, business development, financial analysis, marketing, raising of capital, pricing jobs, human resources, developing key vendor/supplier relationships, developing key banking and investor relationships, etc.

*Structured and marketed project proposals to investors, creditors, buyers and sellers in efforts to raise capital through a combination of bank debt, seller financing, preferred and common equity.

*Built relationships with lenders and investors to facilitate financing of projects. Included negotiating structure and terms with all parties to minimize project risk and maximize profitability.

*Managed all projects for the companies, including development and construction projects, from initiation through closing. Focused on client satisfaction, goal achievement, and flexibility.

*Supervised teams of up to 30 individuals to effectively deliver projects within budget, scope and schedule.

*Risk managed the real estate portfolio, construction projects, loan portfolio, and equity investments.

*Special assets and distressed real estate work (in-house and 3rd party). Negotiate and structure with banks and investors.

Wachovia Securities, LLC

Vice President, Corporate and Investment Banking - Energy & Power July 1993 - July 2003 (10 years 1 month)

•Advised the nation's largest utility and energy companies on issues relative to finance, capital structure, and business growth

*Worked with client's top executives (CEO's, CFO's, SVP's, Treasurers, etc.) to create financing/structuring solutions to meet clients' needs and the firm's goals.

*Marketed corporate and investment banking products including loan syndications, derivatives, equity, investment grade and high yield bonds, M&A advisory, treasury, trust and cash management products, etc.

*Originated, structured, underwrote and co-managed a \$7B portfolio of syndicated and non-syndicated financings to over 100 clients, responsible for all aspects of portfolio risk.

•Authored credit memorandum & underwriting/analysis presented to senior management and credit administration recommending deployment or non-deployment of the firm's capital. Underwriting packages included, among other things, thorough analysis of client's capital structure, leverage, cash flows, projections, sensitivity analysis, collateral analysis, and industry research.

*Managed and trained supporting associates and analysts in the execution of complex financial projects.

Education

Appalachain State University, Walker School of Business MBA, Finance · (1991 - 1993)

University of North Carolina at Charlotte - Belk College of Business BS in Business, Finance, Economics, and Philosophy · (1985 - 1989)